{"tossups": [{"question": "One of these geologic features contains a unique mineral whose closest relatives are picrite and komatiite and whose type locality is the Meimecha-Kotuj province. Ernst and Buchan developed a method for mapping remnants of these features that date to before the Mesozoic era by tracing their precursors to the convergence points of giant radiating dike swarms. These continental features have a concentration of incompatible elements that is intermediate between mid-ocean ridges and ocean island basalts. In the mantle plume hypothesis, these features are plume heads and hotspots are plume tails. The Chicxulub impact event caused accelerated outgassing from one of these features that may have contributed to the Cretaceous extinction. For 10 points, identify these \"stairstep\" landforms created by eruptions from volcanic  ssures, examples of which cover large areas of Siberia and the Deccan plateau.", "answer": "traps [or continental flood basalts; or CFBs; or large igneous provinces; or LIPs; or Siberian traps; or Deccan traps; prompt on basalts or lava  lows; do not accept \"oceanic plateaus\" or \"mantle plumes\"]", "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>traps</u></b> [or <b><u>continental flood basalts</u></b>; or <b><u>CFBs</u></b>; or <b><u>large igneous provinces</u></b>; or <b><u>LIPs</u></b>; or <b><u>Siberian traps</u></b>; or <b><u>Deccan traps</u></b>; prompt on <u>basalts</u> or <u>lava  lows</u>; do not accept \"oceanic plateaus\" or \"mantle plumes\"]", "acceptable": ["traps", "traps", "continental flood basalts", "CFBs", "large igneous provinces", "LIPs", "Siberian traps", "Deccan traps"], "promptable": ["basalts", "lava  lows"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "At the conclusion of a book by this author, the protagonist receives her diamond engagement ring back from her captors, whose other gi t to her was the 9 millimeter bullet they didn't shoot her with. The exiled Miguel Littin disguises himself as a Uruguayan businessman to return to his home country in a  rst-person non ction book by this author that was burned in heaps by the Pinochet regime. Interviews with Alberto Villamizar (vee-yah-mee-SAR) and Maruja (mah-ROO-hah) Pachon formed the basis for his account of ten prisoners of the \"Extraditables.\" This author of Clandestine in Chile daringly exposed incompetence aboard the Caldas in what was meant to be a pu f piece on Luis Alejandro Velasco, forcing the shuttering of his newspaper by Gustavo Rojas Pinilla (ROE-hass pee-NEE-yuh). As a journalist, this author of News of a Kidnapping wrote fourteen editorials for El Espectador that became The Story of a Shipwrecked Sailor. For 10 points, name this non ction author better known for creating Macondo, the setting of his novel One Hundred Years of Solitude.", "answer": "Gabriel Garcia Marquez", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Gabriel Garcia <b><u>Marquez</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Gabriel Garcia Marquez", "Marquez"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This scientist names a dimensionless quantity with a critical value of 1708, above which Andereck, Liu, and Swinney found  low states such as interpenetrating spirals and modulated wavy vortices. This scientist is the  rst namesake of a theorem commonly written \"open parenthesis, omega dot del, close parenthesis, times u, equals zero,\" where omega is angular velocity and u is velocity. A structure named for this scientist has a characteristic angle of pi radians minus the  rst zero of the Legendre polynomial of order one-half, or about 49.3 degrees. This scientist and Maurice Couette name a phenomenon that occurs at high angular velocity for a  luid con ned between two rotating cylinders. He is the second namesake of a phenomenon that occurs due to the force of gravity being exerted by a  luid on another  luid of lower density. For 10 points, identify this scientist who co-names that instability with Lord Rayleigh.", "answer": "Geo frey Ingram Taylor [or G.I. Taylor; 0r critical Taylor number; or Taylor-Proudman theorem; or Taylor angle; or Taylor cone; or Taylor-Couette  low; or Rayleigh-Taylor instability]", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Geo frey Ingram Taylor</u></b> [or <b><u>G.I. Taylor</u></b>; 0r critical Taylor number; or <b><u>Taylor-Proudman</u></b> theorem; or <b><u>Taylor angle</u></b>; or <b><u>Taylor cone</u></b>; or <b><u>Taylor-Couette  low</u></b>; or <b><u>Rayleigh-Taylor instability</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Geo frey Ingram Taylor", "Geo frey Ingram Taylor", "G.I. Taylor", "Taylor-Proudman", "Taylor angle", "Taylor cone", "Taylor-Couette  low", "Rayleigh-Taylor instability"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "An Ando Hiroshige painting of one of these animals from the Hundred Famous Views of Edo alludes to a saying that prostitutes \"bloom in the droppings of Yotsuya.\" Gnarled le t-leaning trees create three vanishing points on a scroll showing one hundred of these animals created by Giuseppe Castiglione. Seven giant sculptures of these animals stand outside the Sun Temple at Konarak in Kalinga. Three defeated Roman emperors appear along with one of these animals in the most famous Naqsh-e Rustam inscription. Emperor Kumaragupta struck coins commemorating his performance of the ashvamedha ritual, which required the sacri ce of these animals. Qing court painting anticipated a discovery about the motion of these animals in the photography of Eadweard Muybridge. For 10 points, name these animals that accompany the soldiers of the Terracotta Army and appear in equestrian portraits.", "answer": "horses", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>horses</u></b>", "acceptable": ["horses", "horses"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In a poem set at this location, the speaker hears \"peals of distant ironical laughter at every word I have written\" and describes himself as \"ba  led, balk'd, bent to the very earth\" in his awareness that \"before all my arrogant poems the real Me stands yet untouch'd, untold, altogether unreach'd.\" In another poem set at this location, the speaker calls himself a \"uniter of here and herea ter, taking all hints to use them, but swi tly leaping beyond them.\" In that poem set at this location, the speaker requests \"a word then, (for I will conquer it,) the word  nal, superior to all,\" and hears whispered in response \"the low and delicious word death.\" The aforementioned poems set at this location describe the \"moaning\" of \"the  erce old mother\" who \"endlessly cries for her castaways.\" For 10 points, name this location, the setting of Walt Whitman poems including \"Out of the Cradle Endlessly Rocking,\" in which the speaker observes a \"he-bird\" sitting \"amid the slapping waves.\"", "answer": "the beach [or the shore; or the strand; or the ocean; or the sea; or Paumanok]", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "the <b><u>beach</u></b> [or the <b><u>shore</u></b>; or the <b><u>strand</u></b>; or the <b><u>ocean</u></b>; or the <b><u>sea</u></b>; or <b><u>Paumanok</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["the beach", "beach", "shore", "strand", "ocean", "sea", "Paumanok"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This book argues that the automation of labor turns \"apparatuses we once handled freely\" into \"shells...as...belong to the body of the turtle.\" It dates the beginning of \"world alienation\" to the research of Galileo, because his discovery of universal scienti c laws caused people to view themselves from Ka ka's \"Archimedean point.\" This book critiques Karl Marx by arguing that his \"communistic  ction\" is inherently present in liberal democracy, because the expropriation of the religious establishment already channeled the \"life process\" from the private to the public. It delineates man as sovereign homo faber from man as unfree animal laborans, but argues that both possess the quality of instrumentality, and thus fall short of the conception of man as zoon politikon (ZOH-oh po-LIT-ik-on) in ancient Athens. This text identi es work, labor, and action as the key forms of activity, with political action being the highest because of its freedom. For 10 points, name this book that reassesses the relationship between the vita activa and vita contemplativa, written by Hannah Arendt.", "answer": "The Human Condition", "category": "Philosophy", "subcategory": "Philosophy", "answer_formatted": "The <b><u>Human Condition</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Human Condition", "Human Condition"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One of these institutions conspired with the king of Sweden in a 1788 plot to start a war with Russia with a false- lag attack on Swedish soldiers at Puumala. Another of them is the site of a 1940 photograph of Hitler with nine newly-promoted  eld marshals a ter the conquest of France. An incident at one of these locations prompted the introduction of the Conspiracy to Murder Bill and the trial of the Fourierist Simon Bernard in Britain, where that incident's perpetrator had created namesake mercury fulminate \"bombs.\" The Union and Security Act provoked a coup attempt at one of these places where Jacob Johan Anckarstrom shot a king identi ed by his Royal Order of the Seraphim star, Gustav III Vasa. Napoleon III agreed to the Treaty of Plombieres a ter, near one of these locations, the Italian nationalist Felice Orsini attempted to assassinate him. On King William I's birthday in 1830, rioters poured out of one of these locations to protest Dutch rule, starting the Belgian Revolution. For 10 points, name this type of institution exempli ed by Paris's Palais Garnier and Milan's La Scala.", "answer": "opera houses", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>opera houses</u></b>", "acceptable": ["opera houses", "opera houses"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Application of sodium amide to a ben\u00c2\u00b7zyl\u00c2\u00b7ic version of these compounds can lead to ortho alkylation in the Sommelet-Hauser rearrangement. They don't contain sulfur, but these molecules can undergo a 1,2 shi t in the presence of a strong base in the Stevens rearrangement. Sil\u00c2\u00b7yl ether protecting groups can be removed by using a  luoride salt of one of these molecules. They're not crown ethers, but salts of these molecules are the most commonly used phase transfer catalysts. One of these compounds is generated with the use of methyl iodide and then eliminated with silver oxide to give the less substituted alkene in the Hofmann elimination. They are most easily obtained by reacting a tertiary amine with an alkyl halide in an SN2 reaction. For 10 points, name these species that contain a hypervalent, positively charged nitrogen atom.", "answer": "quaternary ammonium cations [or quarternary amines; or quaternary ammonium salts]", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>quaternary ammonium cations</u></b> [or <b><u>quarternary amines</u></b>; or <b><u>quaternary ammonium salts</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["quaternary ammonium cations", "quaternary ammonium cations", "quarternary amines", "quaternary ammonium salts"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Thomas Paine's bones are still dispersed across three continents because this man illegally exhumed his remains, shipped them to England, and lost them around Liverpool. G.K. Chesterton admired this man's revisionist History of the Protestant Reformation, which argued that the Tudor reforms were \"brought forth in hypocrisy and per dy.\" This writer likened feckless journalists to his childhood hounds, whom he could distract from the hunt with the smell of red herring. He infamously attacked William Wilberforce for caring more about slaves than English workers, and controversially sided with the Swing Rioters against institutions like the Bank of England and the national debt that he called \"the System.\" He debated Noah Webster under the pseudonym \"Peter Porcupine\" in the United States, and back home in England he disseminated radical views through his Political Register, called the \"Twopenny Trash.\" For 10 points, name this 19th century social critic and Corn Law opponent who chronicled the e fects of industrialization in his Rural Rides.", "answer": "William Cobbett", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "William <b><u>Cobbett</u></b>", "acceptable": ["William Cobbett", "Cobbett"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One passage of this text criticizes the communists who believe they have found the \"deliverance from our evils,\" claiming that the abolition of private property will only lead to increased \"prerogative in the  eld of sexual relationships.\" This text uses the ending of Voltaire's Candide to illustrate the concept of \"de lections,\" which, along with \"substitutive satisfactions\" and \"intoxication,\" are three \"palliative measures\" it de nes. It claims that modern science has turned man into a \"prosthetic god\" who has everything he previously dreamed of. It uses the wars between the Spanish and the Portuguese as an example of the \"narcissism of small di ferences,\" which illustrates the way that aggression is necessary for the cohesion of a community. Opening with a critique of Romain Rolland's \"oceanic feeling,\" it argues that the title construct causes unhappiness by constraining both libido and aggression. For 10 points, name this essay by Sigmund Freud about the malaise caused by the repressive requirements of society.", "answer": "Civilization and Its Discontents [or Das Unbehagen in der Kultur]", "category": "Social Science", "subcategory": "Social Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Civilization and Its Discontents</u></b> [or <b><u>Das Unbehagen in der Kultur</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Civilization and Its Discontents", "Civilization and Its Discontents", "Das Unbehagen in der Kultur"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This thinker produced a two-by-two matrix called the tableau ideologique displaying outgrowths of what he called the \"doux-commerce thesis\" in his paper \"Rival Interpretations of Market Society.\" A ter spending years observing entrepreneurs in Colombia, this economist argued that underdeveloped countries should invest in industries that create \"forward and backward linkages,\" a strategy he called \"unbalanced growth.\" This thinker attacked the usage of \"perversity,\" \"jeopardy,\" and \"futility\" arguments for conservative policies in The Rhetoric of Reaction. Ralph Nader forwarded this man consumer complaints data for his major work, which uses the example of public schools to show how criticizing \"slackening\" institutions can be more e fective than simply leaving them. For 10 points, name this economist, the co-namesake of a monopolization index with Her ndahl, who authored the classic Exit, Voice, and Loyalty.", "answer": "Albert O. Hirschman", "category": "Social Science", "subcategory": "Social Science", "answer_formatted": "Albert O. <b><u>Hirschman</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Albert O. Hirschman", "Hirschman"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Dra ts of this non-choral piece from the Wittgenstein Sketchbook are heavily cited in William Kinderman's book on this piece. At the end of this piece's penultimate section, a fortissimo diminished seventh chord and cadenza-like arpeggio are followed by six bars of Poco adagio block chords culminating in a strange E minor triad. In this piece, a section labeled \"alla 'Notte e giorno faticar' di Mozart\" is followed by a parody of the  nger exercises of Johann Baptist Cramer. This piece climaxes with a fugue in the foreign key of E- lat major, which transitions into a  nal minuet sometimes compared to the Arietta from the composer's 32nd piano sonata. This piece's composer allegedly used the word \"Schuster leck,\" or \"cobbler's patch\", to describe the simple C major waltz on which it is based. For 10 points, name this massive set of piano variations on a theme by an Austrian publisher, a work of Ludwig van Beethoven.", "answer": "the Diabelli Variations [or 33 Variations on a Waltz by Anton Diabelli; or 33 Vera\u0308nderungen u\u0308ber einen Walzer von Anton Diabelli]", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "the <b><u>Diabelli Variations</u></b> [or <b><u>33 Variations on a Waltz by Anton Diabelli</u></b>; or <b><u>33 Vera\u0308nderungen u\u0308ber einen Walzer von Anton Diabelli</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["the Diabelli Variations", "Diabelli Variations", "33 Variations on a Waltz by Anton Diabelli", "33 Vera\u0308nderungen u\u0308ber einen Walzer von Anton Diabelli"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In a dream from this text, two homosocial companions are represented as a cow who loses her horn and a hornless bull. This text describes a ray of light that impregnates Alan the Fair in a genealogy passage that begins with the marriage of a doe and a wolf. This text was discovered in the 19th century by the Archimandrite Palladius. A character in this text creates a bodyguard called the kheshig led by the sons of his regiment commanders; that character also commands Tata-Tonga to create a writing script. Like in the Manas, a character in this text is born clutching a  st-sized blood clot; that character exchanges knucklebones to create a pledge of anda, or brotherhood. The protagonist of this text attacks the Merkids to retrieve his stolen wife, Borte (bor-tuh), along with his friend and rival Jamukha. This text's later chapters describe the fall of the Khwarezmian Kingdom, and it ends in the reign of Ogedei. For 10 points, name this history of Genghis Khan that shares its name with a text by Procopius.", "answer": "the Secret History of the Mongols [or Tobchiyan; or Mongolyn Nuuts Tovchoo]", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "the <b><u>Secret History of the Mongols</u></b> [or <b><u>Tobchiyan</u></b>; or <b><u>Mongolyn Nuuts Tovchoo</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["the Secret History of the Mongols", "Secret History of the Mongols", "Tobchiyan", "Mongolyn Nuuts Tovchoo"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Margaret Ezell challenged the historical assumptions perpetuated by this character's story in her essay on \"The Myth of [this character].\" Recounting how a \"fat, loose-lipped man\" gu fawed at this woman and \"bellowed something about poodles dancing,\" the narrator states, \"He hinted\u00c2\u2014you can imagine what.\" She is buried at a crossroads where omnibuses stop outside the Elephant and Castle. This character's creator speculates that if we \"look past Milton's bogey\" and recognize \"that our relation is to the world of reality and not only to the world of men and women,\" then this character \"will put on the body which she has so o ten laid down\" and be born. She commits suicide a ter becoming pregnant by the actor-manager Nick Greene, whom she meets in London a ter  leeing her home to pursue a career in theatre like her brother. For 10 points, name this hypothetical woman created by Virginia Woolf in A Room of One's Own, the sister of the author of Hamlet.", "answer": "Judith Shakespeare [or Shakespeare's sister before \"sister\" is read; prompt on Shakespeare]", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Judith Shakespeare</u></b> [or <b><u>Shakespeare's sister</u></b> before \"sister\" is read; prompt on <u>Shakespeare</u>]", "acceptable": ["Judith Shakespeare", "Judith Shakespeare", "Shakespeare's sister"], "promptable": ["Shakespeare"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In the 1980s, Edwin Wilson recruited an assortment of these people for the Gaddafi regime, where they became a global hit squad against dissidents like Faisal Zagallai. During one battle, aerial bombardment from an AC-119 Shadow allowed seventeen of them to escape an assault on their camp by PT-76 tanks. The book Horse Soldiers chronicles a ride these people took on horseback to organize movements by uncoordinated warlords. Their namesake \"affair\" dominated headlines when, to protect Project GAMMA, Robert Rheault (\"Roe\") ordered them to dump a doped-up informant into the sea in chains. They were known as \"snake eaters\" to their allies, the Montagnards, whom they trained to form Civil Irregular Defense Groups. A chart-topping \"Ballad\" by Barry Sadler and a propaganda film by John Wayne raised their profile at home. For 10 points, name these counter-insurgency specialists sent as military advisers early in the Vietnam War, named for their distinctive headgear.", "answer": "Green Berets [or United States Army Special Forces; prompt on American soldiers]", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Green Berets</u></b> [or <b><u>United States Army Special Forces</u></b>; prompt on <u>American soldiers</u>]", "acceptable": ["Green Berets", "Green Berets", "United States Army Special Forces"], "promptable": ["American soldiers"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The expansion of a GCN repeat at the  ve prime end of a protein that binds this structure leads to oculo\u00c2\u00b7pharyngeal muscular dystrophy. The rotavirus protein N\u00c2\u00b7S\u00c2\u00b7P\u00c2\u00b73 serves as an analogue of this structure's namesake \"binding protein\" to inhibit association of this structure with e\u00c2\u00b7I\u00c2\u00b7F\u00c2\u00b74. The TRAMP (\"tramp\") complex enhances degradation by the exosome by trimming down these structures. Molecules containing these structures can be isolated with an oligo-d\u00c2\u00b7T column. The addition of this structure  rst requires a cleavage catalyzed by C\u00c2\u00b7P\u00c2\u00b7S\u00c2\u00b7F at an A\u00c2\u00b7A\u00c2\u00b7U\u00c2\u00b7A\u00c2\u00b7A\u00c2\u00b7A sequence. Alternative splicing and di ferential addition of these structures can allow an mRNA molecule to encode di ferent forms of a protein. The  ve prime end of a mature RNA molecule is attached to a GTP cap while the three prime end is attached to this structure. For 10 points, name this extended sequence of adenosine nucleotides added to the three prime end of newly-translated mRNA.", "answer": "poly-A tail [accept poly-adenylation]", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>poly-A tail</u></b> [accept <b><u>poly-adenylation</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["poly-A tail", "poly-A tail", "poly-adenylation"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Jean Dauberval (\"doe\"-ber-vahl) was known for rehabilitating the \"false\" examples of these techniques, which were reversals of the \"true\" or \"noble\" ones and generally thought to be only suitable for depictions of drunks and sailors. Pierre Beauchamp was inspired to create these techniques by observing the fencing masters in the court of Louis XIV. Dauberval's aforementioned \"false\" ones inspired Serge Lifar, who created two of them that are only used in his works. The third of them has been largely abandoned because it is redundant with the   th, while the fourth has both opened and closed variants. These techniques are used to develop turnout, which when perfected involves 180 degrees of combined outward rotation of both legs. For 10 points, name these techniques, the  rst of which requires a dancer's heels to be placed together and her toes to be pointing in opposite directions.", "answer": "foot positions in ballet", "subcategory": "Other Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>foot positions in ballet</u></b>", "acceptable": ["foot positions in ballet", "foot positions in ballet"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Long tracking shots of this desert are coupled with audio of  lm scholar Lotte Eisner reading from the Popol Vuh in Werner Herzog's early documentary Fata Morgana. It is now thought that an eroded dome, and not a meteorite impact, caused the 30 mile diameter-wide Richat structure which is sometimes termed the \"Eye\" of this desert. Ancient depictions of humans in the Roundhead style were succeeded by the pastoral \"Bovidian,\" according to the chronology revealed by the rock art at this desert's site of Tassili. It is the primary habitat of a species of fox that uses its disproportionately large ears to dissipate heat, the fennec. A city on the southern edge of this desert became a center of 16th century Islamic learning due to the establishment of a famous school at its Sankore Mosque. For 10 points, name this site of Timbuktu, the largest desert in the world.", "answer": "Sahara desert", "category": "Geography", "subcategory": "Geography", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Sahara</u></b> desert", "acceptable": ["Sahara desert", "Sahara"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In a poem by this author that opposes the palindromic terms amor and Roma, Tarpeia begs for a retributive \"Rape of the Roman Women.\" Philologists like O. L. Richmond have addressed this author's notorious di  culty by attempting to \"reconstruct\" his poems assuming a monastic bookbinding bungle. In a poem addressed to his friend Tullus, this author apostrophizes the \"Etruscan dust\" covering the bones of a relative who died in a civil war near this poet's birthplace in Umbria. The exemplum of Melanion moaning from wounds dealt by Hylaeus (\"high\"-LEE-us) illustrates this author's love in a poem addressing \"the  rst to trap [him] with her eyes.\" In a late poem by this author, a ghost who claims to live with the blameless wives Andromeda and Hypermnestra haunts this poet for his love a fair with Chloris. This poet's works are collected into the four-book Monobiblos. For 10 points, name this Augustan elegist, a lover of \"Cynthia\" for whom Ezra Pound wrote an \"Homage.\"", "answer": "Sextus Propertius", "subcategory": "Classical Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Sextus <b><u>Propertius</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Sextus Propertius", "Propertius"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Clay from this city is the preferred component of intricate tablets called \"turbahs,\" which are placed below the head in prayer. A popular saying coined by Ali Shariati ends by noting that \"every land is\" this city. It is the site of the Al-Abbas Mosque, which contains the tomb of a standard bearer who carried a bag of water in his teeth a ter his arms were cut o f. An annual pilgrimage to this city takes its name from the Arabic for \"fortieth day\" and o ten ends with a 55-mile walk from Najaf. That pilgrimage, the Arbaeen, is the world's largest annual pilgrimage. This city is the heart of the Remembrance of Muharram, a series of rituals that culminates with mourning processions and mock battles on Ashura. For 10 points, name this Iraqi city which became a major Shi'ite pilgrimage site a ter Ali's son Hussein was martyred at a namesake battle in 680 AD.", "answer": "Karbala", "category": "Religion", "subcategory": "Religion", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Karbala</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Karbala", "Karbala"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "George du Maurier's political cartoon Love's Labours Lost satirizes the use of this activity by upper-class men to  nd suitable husbands for their daughters. This activity was marketed under the Greek name \"Sphairistike\" when it was popularized by Walter Clopton Wing eld in England, where Eric Hobsbawm argues it helped liberate women. Charles VIII of France died a ter colliding with a low-placed lintel on the way to participate in this activity, which Horace Walpole claims killed Frederick, Prince of Wales. A pen-and-ink sketch by Jacques Louis David depicts Jean Sylvain Bailly raising his right hand in a location dedicated to this activity. According to legend, Henry V received pieces of equipment used in this activity as an insulting gi t from the Dauphin. For 10 points, name this popular recreational sport whose highest competitive levels take place at the French Open and Wimbledon.", "answer": "tennis", "subcategory": "Other History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>tennis</u></b>", "acceptable": ["tennis", "tennis"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}], "bonuses": []}